<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2024-01-04T02:02:30+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Aya Al Sabahi.</title><subtitle>Here is where you&apos;ll find my thoughts, projects, and art :)</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Must Reads, Watch &amp;amp; Play</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/entertainment/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Must Reads, Watch &amp;amp; Play" /><published>2023-12-22T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2023-12-22T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/entertainment</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/entertainment/"><![CDATA[<p>I sometimes pretend I’m a really hardcore game critic.
<strong>Mini disclaimer:</strong> Maybe you should not trust a 20 year old who is just trying to figure things out, but I digress.</p>

<h2 id="movies"><span style="color: #8a837d;">Movies</span></h2>
<ul>
  <li><strong>21 Jumpstreet</strong> - It plays on various different tropes that makes the whole thing a comical</li>
  <li><strong>Dead Poets Society</strong> - The movie gives a sense of finding who you are, being genuine, and looking at the world differently.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="shows"><span style="color: #3d5a80;">Shows</span></h2>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Succession</strong> - an absolute MASTERPIECE of a show, I think there is a fine line between comedy and tragedy. The show poses as a drama between a multibillion dollar family most can only dream of, but the show has the perfect ratio of dry humor to drama to make for a combination no other show was able to do before. Although a little slow at times I must admit, it is rather worth it.</li>
  <li><strong>Silicon Valley</strong> - I have to give it to this show to being one of the reasons I got into CS, younger high school me somewhat related to the characters, but also found the very nerdy jokes embedded (haha see what I did there?) quite funny.</li>
  <li><strong>Black Mirror Episodes</strong> - White Bear</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="books--comics"><span style="color: #54717a;">Books &amp; Comics</span></h2>
<p>Comics:</p>
<ul>
  <li>V for Vendetta - 🧠💥</li>
</ul>

<p>Books:</p>

<h2 id="games"><span style="color: #54717a;">Games</span></h2>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Spiderman PS4</strong> - Okay Okay I know what you’re saying, spiderman again, is that a… <em>bias</em>? NO. Hear me out. Insomniac studios have integrated game mechanics, storyline, and animations seamlessly. The mechanics of Spiderman 2 on PS5 and haptics are also pretty dope!</li>
  <li><strong>Detroit: Become Human</strong> - There is some controversy surrounding the game in the sense that the gameplay is not too great, but I feel that if you think of it as an interactive movie, the fact that there are 30 different endings to a story you write and create plays out really nicely and is truly well written.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="entertainment" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[with reasons why of course]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Interesting Links</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/interestinglinks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interesting Links" /><published>2023-12-22T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2023-12-22T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/interestinglinks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/interestinglinks/"><![CDATA[<ul>
  <li><a href="https://ncase.me/trust/">The Evolution of Trust</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="entertainment" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[simply the title]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">cs @ cmu, first sem reflections</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/first-sem/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="cs @ cmu, first sem reflections" /><published>2021-12-20T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2021-12-20T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/first-sem</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/first-sem/"><![CDATA[<p>It’s currently winter break of 2021, I chose to take this time to reflect upon where I am, and where I have come from, and hopefully do a little something in my life. Hence, this website.</p>

<p>Let’s start by speaking of the semester.</p>

<p>I had to learn from many mistakes the hard way, and I had to mentally get pushed, CMU really squeezes every ounce of brain power you have till you are left with nothing but a mushy brain that needs a break.</p>

<p>It has been fun, and it’s been a semester of many firsts. My first fail in an exam. My first crying In a professors office. My first finishing homework minutes before its due. My first time staying up late to work on a project. This semester has left me inspired, and in love with the supportive community I have.</p>

<p>Carnegie Mellon, and university in general is filled with opportunities, it has been great meeting Professor after Professor, learning from them and their life stories. Embarking in the kindness they offered us and the mentorship they have provided. Not only them, I would like to extend a thank you to the course assistants who have taught me a lot, and helped me grow from my mistakes.</p>

<p>Looking back, there was a lot that I wished I could have done differently, but honestly, I wouldn’t have it any other way.</p>

<p>With time upon my hands I previously did not have much of (or rather poorly managed), I’m left to reflect upon life, what my hopes are and who it is I aspire to become.</p>

<p>Well, spoiler alert… I’ve got no idea, and I think it may be like this for a while.</p>

<p>For now I’ll simply enjoy the trip and what it has to offer, including its occasional hurdles.</p>

<p>Till next time!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="uni" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ah, wonderful journey :,)]]></summary></entry></feed>